### Goal:

Obtain an internship or full time entry-level position working in either the computer science or engineering industries, at a position that relies on programming, research, networking, process engineering, and/or system administration skills I have developed academically and professionally as an undergraduate.

#### **Education:**

B.S. Rutgers University New Brunswick Department of Computer Science, Spring 2012

### Relevant work experience:

Engineering Intern - P.I.M. Brands, Summer 2011

Learned about controls and automation engineering with programmable logic controllers in the food industry. Installed and programmed PLC and touchscreen interface equipment used in the manufacture of candy.

<u>Linux Systems Administrator</u> and <u>Research Assistant</u> - Rutgers Newark Psychology Department: <u>Mind-Brain Analysis Lab, October 2010-June 2011</u>

Learned about software tools and hardware used in computational neuroscience research, performed duties of system administrator (file backup, system upgrade, new software testing, system configuration, office networking) for office machines and distributed computation server cluster. Participated in weekly lab meetings, summarized numerous papers and texts about psychology, neuroscience, and cognitive science.

<u>Machine Room Operator - Rutgers University New Brunswick Computer Science Department:</u>
<u>Laboratory for Computer Science Research, February 2009 - August 2011</u>

Performed duties involved in maintenance of hardware and software systems used by the university computer science department students, faculty, and staff. Performed tape and disk-to-disk backups of critical systems via machine room network. First-response helpdesk phone and email ticket system operator. Completed individual and and team projects related to upgrading and replacing different hardware and software systems, or setting up and programming demonstrations of newly purchased department resources.

Research Assistant and Programmer - Rutgers University New Brunswick Psychology Department: Learning and Memory Lab, May 2008 - December 2009

Assisted in psychology research by writing programs to automatically reorganize and improve quality of data from results of in-class "clicker" participation and online student quiz and testing systems. Participated in weekly lab meetings. Worked with modifying the university's open source Sakai system.

### Relevant courses:

Software Engineering, Programming Language Theory, Network Programming, Database Programming, Software Methodology, Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Distributed Systems

# **Programming Languages:**

Java, C/C++, Perl, Java Server Pages (JSP), MySQL, Ladder Logic (RSLogix 5/500/5000), Python, Ruby

# **Relevant Skills:**

Automation engineering, Unix/Linux system administration, TCP/IP network design and administration (industrial, office, and consumer), high-performance research programming